# Aritana Noara

Belo Horizonte, Minas Gerais, Brazil



arinoara@yahoo.com.br



linkedin.com/in/aritana

## **Summary**

Hello,

I am a computer engineer working as a full-stack developer. I am progressing with time and constantly restructuring myself to make more room for more knowledge and experiences that are going to aggregate my job.

https://github.com/aritana

## **Experience**

#### **CIST** Full-stack Developer

CI&T

Jan 2023 - Present (8 months) Working with AngularJs and Java.

#### Android Software Developer Intern

CI&T

Dec 2021 - Jan 2023 (1 year 2 months)

I work with android apps, code maintenance, unit, and Component testing.

### Java software developer intern

CI&T

Feb 2021 - Dec 2021 (11 months)

I worked with microservice architecture using Java Spring Boot, jenkins, Postman, Unit Tests, Rest Assured, Jira, Intellij and other technologies.

## Sap Abap Developer Intern

Sigga Technologies

Aug 2019 - Jan 2021 (1 year 6 months)

I worked in the product and innovation team, responsible for the maintenance and improvements in the code of products integrated into SAP technology, specifically in the PM module (Plant Maintenance). We used the object-oriented language ABAP, Web Dynpro Framework, and SQL language.

## Natural Gas Supervision and Control Technician

Companhia de Gas de Minas Gerais SA (GASMIG)

Sep 2009 - Aug 2016 (7 years)

Admitted via public tender, I took over as Operation and Maintenance Technician. Responsible for checking customer measurement systems and monitoring calibration at natural gas delivery points.

I finished my cycle at the System Operations Center as a Supervision and Control technician, a sector where I worked with administrative control, monitoring the operation of the entire network of the state of Minas Gerais, responsible for the shift for risk and emergency management.

#### **Electromechanical Technician**

Gega Pecas E Servicos

Aug 2008 - Apr 2009 (9 months)

I worked in the manufacture and maintenance of machines.

I worked in several segments: dismantling, cleaning, painting, electrical and electronic maintenance, and connecting electric motors.



#### **Mechanical Technician Intern**

ArcelorMittal Brasil

Feb 2007 - Sep 2007 (8 months)

I worked in a sector in creation called: Maintenance Methods. The sector's logic was to outline reliability studies and best practices in the maintenance of the unit's assets.



#### Electromechanical technician Intern

Comau

Mar 2006 - Sep 2007 (1 year 7 months)

I worked on making manuals for machines that the sector produced, I had a lot of use of macros, advanced excel, and text translation.



#### Mechanical technician Intern

ArcelorMittal Brasil

Aug 2005 - Jan 2006 (6 months)

I worked in the production department: Trefilarias. I had contact with the SAP system, security standards, management, making spreadsheets and taught to think in a technical way. Having the first contact with big machines.

#### **Education**



## Centro Federal de Educação Tecnológica de Minas Gerais

Bachelor's degree in Computer Engineering, Computer Science

Jul 2015 - Dec 2022

The Computer Engineer will work in the design and development of computer hardware and software systems in software and electronics industries, telecommunications and industrial automation companies. Will provide consultancy in Information Technology both in financial institutions and in teaching and research institutions.



#### SENAI - Alvimar Carneiro de Resende

Associate degree in electronics, Electrical and Electronics Engineering Feb 2015 - Jul 2016

Centro Federal de Educação Tecnológica de Minas Gerais

Associate degree in electromechanical 2006 - 2008

## Senai Michels Michels

Associate degree in mechanics

2004 - 2006

The mechanics technician is a qualified professional who works in the installation and maintenance services of industrial machinery and equipment, coordinating work teams and assisting in the elaboration of projects and in the execution of drawings of industrial equipment and its components. Provide services in the areas of machining and maintenance of machines and equipment.

## **Licenses & Certifications**

- Java Exceções: Aprenda a criar, lançar e controlar exceções Alura 7a4fd86b-4d82-42dc-8e96-58855c888725
- Git e Github: Controle e compartilhe seu código Alura 9782b899-687b-4a75-af5f-60f82dc8a8da
- Swagger parte 1: Crie uma documentação APIs REST Alura fc75efcb-efc1-43b8-8a84-dd6ccfe65bff
- Java e java.lang: Programe com a classe Object e String Alura 3cc29b01-22cf-4720-9013-f8e90f536fce
- Spring Boot API REST: Construa uma API Alura f2b3d5d7-7e80-4473-8189-7c2770434ca2
- Mocks em Java: Conhecendo o Mockito Alura a789b513-4b12-47ae-bb6f-819fb9b72f19
- Java e java.util: Coleções, Wrappers e Lambda expressions Alura b183c48d-b274-439c-947b-72457144f268
- TDD e Java: Testes automatizados com JUnit Alura 194fc67c-366e-4b4c-9f76-b631a72b1785
- SOLID com Java: Princípios da programação orientada a objetos Alura 244d72c9-0d29-4586-ae1e-f5ef0fb0b296
- **3 Jenkins: Integração contínua** Alura

- Fundamentos Quality Assurance: TestPlan e boas práticas Alura f983b6fb-0ce5-461c-86cc-58828c12e605
- Testes de Integração: Testes de SQL e DAOs automatizados em Java Alura 9a8848f2-0044-4925-a88f-3ad553d0c6bc
- Inglês Intermediário 2 Fundação CEFETMINAS FCM 77454129
- Java Servlet: Fundamentos da programação web Java Alura b1244858-4fc2-4d71-b0d7-593510c39353
- Spring Boot API Rest: Segurança da API, Cache e Monitoramento Alura 094f8f1b-fe8d-44a1-b0ef-4e93e7e612a6
- Java Servlet: Autenticação, autorização e o padrão MVC Alura 0fb4ee71-5ab8-42e3-a6bb-bb90760b61bf
- Microsserviços: Padrões de projeto Alura 1fece5c2-17c9-4b17-bdf7-2edf636a12ae
- HTTP: Entendendo a web por baixo dos panos Alura 11d32200-b919-459c-a388-da2a0cb6b2d3
- Android com Kotlin: Crie o seu primeiro app Alura 7dc653d9-410a-42fc-959e-74831a12380d
- Inglês Pós Intermediário 1 Fundação CEFETMINAS FCM 32643953
- Inglês Pós-intermediário 2 Fundação CEFETMINAS FCM 17610245
- Voxy Proficiency Achievement Certificate High Intermediate Voxy 63169b46bf29d3223473979d
- Amazon S3: manipule e armazene objetos na nuvem Alura 50f1c28b-cf42-4904-89fa-24a6398c66c3

- **Android com Kotlin: criando um app** Alura 7dc653d9-410a-42fc-959e-74831a12380d
- Java e Clean Architecture: descomplicando arquitetura de software Alura 153538b6-fadc-4d77-9f4c-0486b038c2d9
- **Docker: criando e gerenciando containers** Alura fdea9eed-9881-4f43-9aa3-c01f8aec5b21
- Design Patterns em Java I: boas práticas de programação Alura 57d26417-df9b-415b-9f7a-034970a4dc0e
- Design Patterns em Java II: avançando nas boas práticas de programação Alura 61025d46-5820-4e3d-bd5f-3c141f861997
- React: desenvolvendo com JavaScript Alura 4e444654-8f95-47cd-990b-50af4bcce212

#### **Skills**

AngularJS • Git • Bitbucket • Dependency Injection • SOLID Design Principles • Microservices • Postman API • postman • Swagger API • Spring Boot